

Computational Linguist

♀ New Brunswick, NJ

@ yc825@linguistics.rutgers.edu

% pterosdiacos.github.io

in www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cao-pdiacos

EXPERIENCES

Ontology Linguist

Facebook via PRO Unlimited

1 08/2019 - 10/2019

Redmond, WA

- Worked at Assistant Cross-Functional Group
- Prototyped models for cross-domain semantic parsing for question answering, using PyTorch
- Automated inferences and sub-ontology extraction in OWL 2 ontology knowledge graphs, using Python

Teaching Assistant

Rutgers University

1 09/2018 - 08/2020

New Brunswick, NJ

• Courses taught: Introduction to Linguistic Theory, Invented Languages

Research Assistant

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

12/2014 - 07/2015

♦ Hong Kong, China

- Worked at Center for Sign Linguistics and Deaf Studies
- Provided linguistic expertise and assisted in developing a Chinese grammatical knowledge assessment software for deaf/hard of hearing children

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

Ph.D. in Linguistics

09/2016 - Present

♀ New Brunswick, NJ

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

M.A. in Chinese Linguistics & Language Acquisition

1 09/2013 - 06/2014

♀ Hong Kong, China

Sichuan Normal University

B.A. in Teaching Chinese as a Second Language

1 09/2009 - 06/2013

Chengdu, China

PUBLICATIONS

 Automated fact-value distinction in court opinions European Journal of Law and Economics 2020.

A Yu Cao, Daniel Chen & Elliot Ash.

Automated classification of fact vs. value statements in written iudicial decisions

· Investigating BERT's knowledge of language: Five analysis methods with NPIs

Proceedings of EMNLP 2019.

Alex W., Yu Cao & 14 others (equal contribution). Team role: constructed and conducted the main transfer learning experiments

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Linguistics

specialized in computational linguistics, semantics, syntax, discourse analysis. Strong criticalthinking and problem-solving

Computation 10+ years of experiences in algorithms and data structure. The First Prize in National Olympiad in Informatics in Provinces 2007, China

PROJECTS

Graph representation of meaning

(dissertation research (7 repo)

- Designed a graph based semantic representation that encodes natural language quantification and plurality.
- Provided its model-theoretical interpreter.
- Developed a CCG-based semantic parser constructing graphs from texts.

Incremental topological sorting (LingBuzz post)

- Designed algorithms for topological sorting under uncertain conditions.
- Improved on time complexity with dynamic updating strategies.

SKILLS

Machine learning algorithms, NLP/NLU Python, C, Scikit-learn, PyTorch, Tensorflow Linguistic analysis, symbolic logic, statistics

ML/NLP Coursework

 Natural language processing (?) **#** 09/2020 m HSE@Coursera

• Bayesian methods for machine learning 🔾 **1** 08/2020 **m** HSE@Coursera

 Introduction to deep learning • **1** 07/2020 m HSE@Coursera

Machine learning

07/2020

m Stanford@Coursera

· Project seminar: Linguistic knowledge in reusable sentence encoders **m** 05/2019 **m** NYU

• Graph formalisms for meaning representations **m** NASSLLI@CMU **#** 07/2018

• NLU & computational semantics **6** 05/2018 **m** NYU

Statistical NLP

6 05/2013

m U Columbia@Coursera